Connie Regan-Blake collection, 1974-2014
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Manuscripts ca. 1976-1998
  - Subseries J: Newspapers, 1971-2015
    - Newspapers, 1979-2015 (Box-folder 21/4-5)
      Mountain Xpress (April 2015), Sidmouth Herald (August 1979), Asheville Citizen-Times (October 1993), Globe (November 1984), Times-News, Hendersonville, NC (October 1987), Colusa Sun-Herald (May 1979), Pittsburgh Post-Gazette (December 1980), Herald Dispatch and Bisbee Review (October 1981), Landmark Magazine (May 1981) Statesville Record and Landmark (May 1983), and Seventh Pillar (April 1983).
    - Newspapers, 1983-2011 (Box-folder 21/6-7)
      Herald & Tribune (October 1990), Asheville Citizen-Times (1983, August 1987, April 1989, July 1988, September 1988, October 2006), New Directions for Women (November/December 1988), Baytown Sun (August 1989), AmericanWay (September 1982), Guardian (October 1988) Saturday Evening Post (April 1988), Virginian-Pilot (October 1985), Philadelphia Daily News (January 1986), Phoenix Gazette (February 1988), Times-News, Hendersonville, NC (October 1987), Watauga Democrat (August 1985), Chattanooga News-Free Press (October 1985), Deland Sun News (May 1988), Piedmont People (April 1988), News and Observer (July 1987), Paragould Daily Press (June 2011), and Times West Virginian (October 2009).
    - Newspapers, 1974-2013 (Box-folder 21/8-9)
      Asheville Citizen-Times (March 2011, August 2010, October 1999, January 2000, June 2013), Post & Courier (May 2008), Mountain Xpress (August 2010), Chattanooga News-Free Press (October 1974), Kingsport News (October 1974), Christian Science Monitor (November 1977), Charlotte Observer (October 1976), Loyola of the South (March/April 1979), Florida Times (October 1991), Times Union (August 2002), Rapid River Art Magazine (March 2005), LaGrange Daily News (February 2013) Troup County News (February 2013), Troup County Banner (February 2013), Chattanooga News - Free Press (August 1974), Knoxville News-Sentinel (July 1976), and Asheville Citizen-Times (March 2013, June 2013).
    - Newspapers, 1974-2010 (Box-folder 22/1-2)
      Asheville Tribune (August 2010), Asheville Citizen-Times (November 2009, May 2007, December 1978), Our State (November 2006), Greensboro Daily News (March 1982), Charlotte Observer (March 1989), Chattanooga News-Free Press (October 1974, February 1976), Johnson City Press-Chronicle (April 1975), Chattanooga Times (October 1974, April 1996, February 1976), Virginia Beach Beacon (February 1976), Old Dominion University News (March 1976), Virginian-Pilot (October 1976), Mace and Crown (October 1976), Arts Journal (August 1978), Pittsburgh Press (November 1978), Intelligence (November 1978), and Newport Plain Talk (October 1974).
    - Newspapers, 2009-2015 (Box-folder 22/3-4)
      Asheville Citizen-Times (July 2014, March 2015, April 2012, October 2011, June 2013, September 2013), Storyline (2011), Out and About (July 2011), Union Democrat (March 2012), Story City Herald (September 2015), Mountain Xpress (April 2015), and Spartanburg Herald-Journal (April 2009).
    - Newspapers, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 22/5-6)
      Articles on NAPPS: Herald & Tribune (October 1990, September 2002, September 1992, September 1993), and Johnson City Press (September and October 1992, October 1993, October 1990).
    - Newspapers, 1974 (Box-folder 22/7)
      Articles on NAPPS: Kingsport News (October 1974), Johnson City Press-Chronicle (October 1974), and Herald & Tribune (October 1974).
    - Newspapers, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 22/8)
      Asheville Citizen-Times (May 2007, October 1999, October 2006, August 2007), The Herald (March 2004), Journal of Tar Heel Tellers (December 1995), Our State (November 2006), and Mountain Traditions (2006).
    - Newspapers, 1977-1994 (Box-folder 23/1-5)
      The News Herald (June 1981), Tyler Courier Times (March 1981), News-Democrat (May 1981), New Age (December 1981), Asheville Citizen-Times (October 1981, August 1980, July 1981, August 1981, April 1982, June 1982, September 1980, March 1980, May 1982), Times Picayune (April 1981), Lenoir News-Topic (September 1981), Tempe Daily News (April 1981), El Paso Times (March 1981), Midland Reporter-Telegram (April 1981), Mountaineer (October 1981), New York Times (October 1981), Union Banner (November 1981), Warren Times Observer (May 1981), Laurens County Advertiser (May 1984), News-Press (January 1982), Daily News-Miner (July 1982), Advocate (August 1982), Philadelphia Inquirer (October 1980), Herald & Tribune (October 1980), Pittsburgh Post-Gazette (December 1980), Akron Beacon Journal (May 1980), and Vancouver Sun (July 1980) Rocky Mount NC Telegram (August 1987), Asheville Citizen-Times (February 2007), Women's Center of Jacksonville (June 2002), Western News (July 1979), Times-Union (August 2002), Detroit Free Press (October 1984), Enterprise (October 1987), News & Observer (July 1987), Grosse Pointe News (September 1983), Journal-Patriot (February 1977), Asheville Citizen-Times (September 1980, March 1995), Loyola of the South (March/April 1979), Arts Journal (September 1980), Jacksonville Journal (March 1986), Hartford Courant (September 1977), Nashville Banner (December 1978), Times Picayune (April 1981), Florida Times-Union (September 1980), Arts Journal (October 1985), Times-News (July 1986), St. Tammany Picayune (November 1992), Metro Times (January 1989), Birmingham News (October 1979), NFP (March 1986), Chattanooga Times (January 1986), Arts Journal (March 1979), Out 'N About (December/January 1994/95), News & Observer (April 1979), Asheville Citizen-Times (June 1994, December 1978), Journal-Patriot (April 1994, June 1978), Nashville Banner (December 1978), Beckley Post- Herald (November 1978), and Loyola of the South (March/April 1979).
    - Newspapers, 1980-2006 (Box-folder 24/1-7)
      Lansing State Journal (November 1996), Tryon Daily Bulletin (November 2000), News and Observer (July 1987), Brackety-Ack (January 1996), Oklahoma Gazette (February 2000), Dayton Daily News (November 1982), Picayune (December 1991), Asheville Citizen-Times (June 1992, October 1992, April 1989, October 1993, April 2004, December 1991, May 2004, October 2006, August 2007, October 1983, November 1994), Greenville News (March 1980), Getaway (July 1989), West Neighbors (August 1989), Charlotte Observer (March 1989), Ann Arbor News (February 1989), Mountain Traditions (2006), Journal of Tar Heel Tellers (December 1995), Philadelphia Daily News (January 1986), Virginian-Pilot (October 1985), Chattanooga News-Free Press (October 1985), Watauga Democrat (August 1985, February 1996), Arts Journal (October 1985), Roanoke Times (January 1996), Mountain Times (February 1996), Centre Daily News (October 1995), Herald Journal (March 1996), and Daily Hampshire Gazette (November 1995) Greenville Sun (February 1978), River Reporter (May 1978), Chattanooga News-Free Press (March 1978), Sunday Record (June 1978), Inter-Mountain Elkin (April 1978), The Torch (September 1978), Johnson City Press-Chronicle (October 1975), Times-Union and Journal (October 1976), Knoxville News Sentinel (July 1976), Intelligence (November 1978), Pittsburgh Press (November 1978), Asheville Citizen-Times (June 1991, October 1992, September 1988), Jacksonville Journal (September 1988), New York Times (October 1977), Currents (June 1990), Herald & Tribune (October 1990), Tempo (September 2000), and Chattanooga (April 1996) Asheville Citizen-Times (March 2011, February 2006, July 1986, July 1988, April 1979), Rocky Mount NC Telegram (August 1987), Ledger-Star (October 1985), Atlanta Constitution (October 1979), Baytown Sun (August 1989), Plow (October 1978), Arts Journal (September 1980), Journal-Patriot (February 1977, June 1978), Statesville Record & Landmark (February 1977), Florida Times-Union (February 1978), Aslan (August 1976), Elizabethton Star (January 1976), Amityville Record (May 1977), Time Herald Record (June 1978), Winnipeg Tribune (July 1978), News Register (April 1978), and The Torch (September 1978).
    - Newspapers, 1971-2015 (Box-folder 25/1-7)
      Asheville Citizen-Times (November 1992, March 2015, June 2013, August 2007, October 2006, March 2011), Kingsport Times News (December 1988), New Directions for Women (November/December 1988), Chattanooga News-Free Press (October 1974), Chattanooga Pulse (May 2006), Johnson City Press (October 2002), Greensboro Daily News (March 1982), LaGrange Daily News (March 2013), and Register-Herald (March 2007) Asheville Citizen-Times (October 1989, June 1991, March 1989, September 1982, September 1992), Chattanooga News-Free Press (December 1991), West Neighbors (August 1989), Parkway Milepost (1993), The Herald Weekend (May 1991), Currents (June 1990), Blue Ridge Digest (1989), Johnson City Press-Chronicle (October 1982), and Herald & Tribune (September 1992) Herald & Tribune (October 1975), Johnson City Press-Chronicle (October 1975, January 1980), Slidell Picayune (November 1992), Chattanooga News-Free Press Chronicle (October 1974), Asheville Citizen-Times (September 1982, August 1991, September 1988), Getaway (September 1991), Blue Ridge Digest (Summer 1990), News-Register (November 1978), and Islander News (January 1990) Roanoke Times (March 2004), Asheville Citizen-Times (May 2004), and Palm Beach Daily News (March 2004).
- Series 2: Sound Recordings, 1982-2014, undated
  - Subseries A: Audiocassettes
    - Mountain sweet talk Act I, 1988, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR01)
      Play created by The Folktellers.
    - Mountain sweet talk Act II, 1988, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR02)
    - Spirits walk: chilling tales for teenagers and adults, 1999, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR03)
      Five ghost stories: "Rag doll," "Two white horses," "Mr. Fox," "Mary Culhane," and "The veil."
    - Stories for the road, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR04)
      Stories include "Peanut butter," "The sneakout mountain diary," "Yellow ribbon," "Jazzy three bears," "The dancing man," and "Come again in the spring."
    - The Folktellers: Chillers, 1983, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR05)
      Compilation of ghost stories: "Mary Culhane and the dead man," "The Calico coffin," "Old man all skin and bones," "How to turn into a witch," "Mr. Fox," "The wonderful wood," and "The ghoul."
    - Christmas at the home place, 1992, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR06)
      Stories and songs performed by The Folktellers and friends. This includes the story, Charlie Franklin's Truce Flag, and the song Beautiful Star of Bethlehem. The album has 11 titles.
    - The Folktellers: White horses whippoorwills, 1983, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR07)
      "Two white horses," "Old drye frye," "Jazzy three bears," "No news," "Mountain whippoorwills," and "Oliver Hyde's dishcloth concert."
    - Tales to grow on, 1982, 1 sound cassette: analog. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR08)
      Includes six traditional and adapted tales.
  - Subseries B: Optical media
    - Tales of humor, undated, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR09)
      Includes six personal and adapted tales. The disc also includes a note and a signature from the storyteller, Larry Kelley.
    - Little, but oh my!: the story of Berte Olson, Puget Sound's first female ferryboat Captain, 2004, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR10)
      Researched, written, and performed by Jill Johnson. The story is a recreation of the life of Bert Olson, who was the first woman to own her own ferryboat company.
    - Tea and cookies and other threatened species, 2008, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR11)
      Four stories recorded live at the Charles and Myrtle's Coffeehouse, Chattanooga, Tennessee. Stories told by Jim Pfitzer.
    - West Virginia storytellers... live!, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR12)
      Compilation of six storytellers telling children stories. The tellers include Donna Washington, Granny Sue Holsten, Donna Wilson, Jo Ann Dadisman, Rich Knoblich, and Suzi "Mama" Whaples.
    - Stories for the road and to grow on: The Folktellers' award-winning classics, 2006, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR13)
      A compilation of 11 stories and songs performed individually or as The Folktellers.
    - Tales of Appalachia: stories and chamber music, 2004, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR14)
      Four stories and music by the Kandinsky Trio and Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Tales from Timpanogos Storytelling Festival, 2014, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR15)
      Connie Regan-Blake tells "Rag doll" and a ghost story at the 2014 Timpanogos Storytelling Festival.
    - Dive into stories: a telling performance, 2006, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR16)
      Seven true-life stories and traditional tales by Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Chilling ghost stories, 1999, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR17)
      Five ghost stories told by Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Most of all, 2008, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR18)
      Stories by Laura Boosinger and Josh Gofarth.
    - An unmarked path, undated, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR19)
      Story by Lethan Candlish.
    - Chanukah with Elijah, undated, 1 sound disc; digital. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR20)
      Story by Elijah Liebowitz
  - Subseries C: Reel to reel
    - Chillers, 1987, 1 sound tape reel (master): analog; 3 3/4 ips. 10 in. (Item-id AFC 2015/003: SR21)
      Original master of the sound recording Chillers. The date written on the original tape box is October 27, 1987. It also gives information about the quality and sound of the recording.
- Series 3: Graphic Images, ca. 1969-2007
  - Subseries A: Color negatives
    - The Folktellers at various locations, 1983, undated, 6 35mm color negative strips; 25 images (Box-folder 26/1)
      Images of The Folktellers at events.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 110 color negative strips, 441 images (Box-folder 26/2)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, 1981, 63 35mm color negative strips; 254 images (Box-folder 26/3)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 11 35mm color negative strips; 39 images (Box-folder 26/4)
      Images of the Folktellers and other individuals at events.
    - The Folktellers at the International Storytelling Festival and Conference, 1985, 18 35mm color negative strips; 69 images (Box-folder 26/5)
      Images of The Folktellers at the NAPPS Festival and Conference.
    - Mountain sweet talk, undated, 7 35mm color negative strips; 26 images (Box-folder 26/6)
      Images of The Folktellers on the set of their play.
    - The Folktellers, 1984, undated, 4 60mm color negatives; 160 35mm color negatives; 691 images (Box-folder 27/1)
      Images of The Folktellers at events, including the International Storytelling Festival, in Jonesborough, Tennessee.
    - The Folktellers, 1986, 4 35mm color negative strips; 16 images (Box-folder 27/2)
      Images of The Folktellers at Christopher's Taylor log cabin in Jonesborough, Tennessee.
    - The Folktellers, undated, 39 35mm color negative strips; 2 60mm color negatives; 142 images (Box-folder 27/3)
      Images of The Folktellers performing with other performers.
    - Gingko and Serpico, undated, 2 35mm color negative strips; 8 images (Box-folder 27/4)
      Includes images of a dog and a fireplace.
    - Mom's surprise party, 1982, 8 35 mm color negative strips; 33 images (Box-folder 27/5)
      Images of a gathering identified as Mom's surprise party, February, 1982.
    - Mountain sweet talk, undated, 7 35mm color negative strips; 25 images (Box-folder 27/6)
      Images of The Folktellers performing onstage.
    - Mountain sweet talk, undated, 10 35mm color negative strips; 38 images (Box-folder 27/7)
      Includes images of the Folktellers performing onstage.
    - The Folktellers, 1985, 7 35mm color negative strips; 20 images (Box-folder 28/1)
      Images of The Folktellers and other individuals in a clothing store.
    - The Folktellers, 1986, 3 35mm color negative strips; 11 images (Box-folder 28/2)
      Includes images of The Folktellers performing Mountain sweet talk. Also includes images of flowers. Original envelope is labelled, "Hele Land's B/day with Mom and Gus; Flowers at Beetree, 01 June, 1986."
    - The Folktellers, undated, 2 35mm color negative strips; 7 images (Box-folder 28/3)
      Images of The Folktellers with Jane Yolen and the St. Louis Deaf Community. Also includes images of other individuals.
    - The Folktellers performing at various locations, undated, 20 35mm color negative strips; 66 images (Box-folder 28/4)
    - Mountain sweet talk, undated, 29 35mm color negative strips; 117 images (Box-folder 28/5)
      Images of The Folktellers and production crew on the set of their play.
    - Mountain sweet talk, undated, 1 35mm color negative; 4 images (Box-folder 28/6)
    - Mountain sweet talk at Folk Art Center, 1986, 4 35mm color negative strips; 19 images (Box-folder 28/7)
      Images of The Folktellers and others on the set of their play.
    - Mountain sweet talk set, 1986, 4 35mm color negative strips; 24 images (Box-folder 28/8)
      Images of The Folktellers along with other individuals on the set of their play. Original envelope is labelled, "MST cast and crew Cissy and Gary Gerhardts, 04 July, 1986."
    - Mountain sweet talk set, 1986, 3 35mm color negative strips; 14 images (Box-folder 28/9)
      Images of individuals working. Original envelope is labelled, "removing rug from Stonecastle, working on Mountain sweet talk set at the Folk Art Center."
    - The Folktellers at various locations, 1985, 38 35mm color negative strips; 133 images (Box-folder 29/1)
    - The Folktellers, Jonesborough cabin, 1986, 4 35mm color negative strips; 16 images (Box-folder 29/2)
      Images are labelled, "Jonesborough cabin, 1986."
    - Mountain sweet talk, Mohegan College, 1986, 2 35mm color negative strips; 12 images (Box-folder 29/3)
    - Mountain sweet talk, 1986, 7 35mm color negative strips; 23 images (Box-folder 29/4)
      Includes images from a practice session of the play.
    - Mountain sweet talk, 1986, 5 35mm color negative strips; 18 images (Box-folder 29/5)
      Images from the opening night cast party.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 10 35mm color negative strips; 36 images (Box-folder 30/1)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 16 35mm color negative strips; 41 images (Box-folder 30/2)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 73 35mm color negative strips; 272 images (Box-folder 30/3)
      Includes images of the Folktellers at a pow wow. Also includes images of The Folktellers interacting with the audience and other performers.
    - The Folktellers, undated, 19 35mm color negative strips; 88 images (Box-folder 30/4)
      Images of The Folktellers at events including a parade.
    - Mountain sweet talk and The Folktellers, 1986-1988, 1 4x5 in. color negative, 15 35mm color negative strips; 52 images (Box-folder 30/5)
      Images of The Folktellers on the set of their play. Also includes publicity images, 1984-1988.
    - The Folktellers, undated, 6 35mm color negative strips; 21 images (Box-folder 31/1)
      Includes images of The Folktellers on the set of their play. Also includes images of publicity shots and resource products of The Folktellers.
    - The Folktellers at a concert, undated, 3 35mm color negative strips; 8 images (Box-folder 31/2)
      Includes images of The Folktellers at a concert.
    - The Folktellers at a concert, undated, 6 35mm color negative strips; 15 images (Box-folder 31/3)
      Images of The Folktellers at a concert.
    - The Folktellers at Jonesborough Cabin, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 3 images (Box-folder 31/4)
      Images of The Folktellers at the cabin, Jonesborough, Tennessee.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, 1985, 7 35mm color negative strips; 26 images (Box-folder 31/5)
      Images of The Folktellers celebrating Christmas, 1985.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 7 35mm color negative strips; 21 images (Box-folder 31/6)
      Includes images of different persons and buildings.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 7 35mm color negative strips; 20 images (Box-folder 31/7)
      Images of The Folktellers at events. Also includes landscape photographs.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 10 35mm color negative strips; 27 images (Box-folder 31/8)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 2 images (Box-folder 31/9)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 32 35mm color negative strips; 102 images (Box-folder 31/10)
      Includes The Folktellers at events. Also includes landscape photographs.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 16 35mm color negative strips; 47 images (Box-folder 31/11)
      Images of The Folktellers interacting with the audience and performers at a pow wow.
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 4 images (Box-folder 31/12)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 21 35mm color negative strips; 79 images (Box-folder 31/13)
    - The Folktellers at various locations, undated, 8 35mm color negative strips; 26 images (Box-folder 31/14)
    - Individuals at various locations, undated, 7 35mm color negative strips; 7 images (Box-folder 31/15)
      Images of individuals at undisclosed locations.
    - Individuals at various locations, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 3 images (Box-folder 31/16)
    - Individuals at various locations, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 4 images (Box-folder 31/17)
    - Individuals at various locations, undated, 6 35mm color negative strips; 17 images (Box-folder 31/18)
    - Mountain sweet talk, Washington Flyer magazine, undated, 1 35mm color negative; 1 image (Box-folder 31/19)
      Images of Connie holding a banjo and Barbara holding a lumberjack. These negatives were loaned to the Washington Flyer magazine, to be included in the September/October issue of the magazine.
    - Outdoor activities, undated, 4 35mm color negative strips; 11 images (Box-folder 31/20)
      Images of persons engaging in outdoor activities.
    - Outdoor activities, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 3 images (Box-folder 31/21)
    - Outdoor photographs, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 2 images (Box-folder 31/22)
    - Outdoor photographs, undated, 8 35mm color negative strips; 22 images (Box-folder 31/23)
    - undated, 6 35mm color negative strips; 25 images (Box-folder 31/24)
      Unidentified images.
    - Unidentified individuals, undated, 1 35mm color negative strip; 2 images (Box-folder 31/25)
      Images of unidentified persons.
  - Subseries B: Black-and-white negatives
    - Chillers, undated, 1 35mm black-and-white negative strip; 3 images (Box-folder 32/1)
      Images of The Folktellers Chillers' album cover.
    - Chillers, 1983, 3 35mm black-and-white negative strips; 12 images (Box-folder 32/2)
      Includes images of The Folktellers performing onstage including publicity shots.
    - The Folktellers, undated, 5 35mm black-and-white negative strips; 3 4x5 in. black-and-white copy negatives; 3 120mm black-and-white negative strips; 28 images (Box-folder 32/3)
      Images of The Folktellers on set including publicity shots.
    - The Folktellers and Doc McConnell, et al. undated, 7 35mm black-and-white negative strips; 26 images (Box-folder 32/4)
      Includes images of The Folktellers performing. Also includes images of Doc Mc Connell and other individuals.